Guide to the Geraldine Page Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- November 2005 Acquisition, 1865-1999
  - Audiocassettes (Box 78)
    - James Galway, "Mozart: The Two Flute Concertos and Andante, K. 315", 1977; 1 (Box 78)
      This is a commerical audiocassette. It has not been digitized.
    - Andrés Segovia-Reveries, 1978; 1 (Box 78)
    - "Chopin: Piano Concerto No. 2", 1972; 1 (Box 78)
    - "Tchaikovsky: Symphony No. 5 in K Minor, Op. 64", undated; 1 (Box 78)
    - "Grieg/Rachmaninoff: Philippe Entremont, Piano", 1973; 1 (Box 78)
    - "Eugene Fodor Plays Fritz Kreisler", 1977; 1 (Box 78)
    - "La Boheme"; "Beethoven", undated; 1 (Box 78, Item barcode 39002104611968)
    - "EGBDF", undated; 1 (Box 78, Item barcode 39002104611976)
    - The Who, "My Generation", undated; 1 (Box 78)
    - "Dvorák: Symphony No. 9", undated; 1 (Box 78)
  - Miscellaneous personal items including magnifying glass, keys on a chain, etc., undated (Box 79)
  - Oversize
    - Geraldine Page, photographs, circa 1962; 2 (Box 80 (Oversize))
    - Photograph of a child, undated (Box 80 (Oversize))
    - Photographs of children, a man and a night scene, inscribed by Genen Smith, circa 1955; 4 (Box 80 (Oversize))
    - Issue of Derrière Le Miroir (Paris: Éditions Pierre A Feu) featuring the artword of Saul Steinberg, 1953 April (Box 80 (Oversize))
    - Three drawings, two sketches, one watercolor, undated (Box 80 (Oversize))
    - Oil paintings on canvas board, unsigned, undated; 4 (Box 80 (Oversize))
    - Children's paper doll pieces and a game board, undated (Box 80 (Oversize))
    - Photographs of Page from stage and film, including The Beguiled,; publicity portraits; and group photographs, 1950-1986; 6 (Box 81 (Oversize))
    - Photographs of Page from stage and film, 1950-1985; 3 (Box 82 (Oversize))
    - Issue of Esquire magazine featuring article on Sweet Bird of Youth by Tennesse Williams (2 copies), 1959 April (Box 82 (Oversize))
    - Show Magazine, 1961 October (Box 82 (Oversize))
    - Life magazine issue, 1969 October 17 (Box 82 (Oversize))
    - "Miss Moffat," vocal score by Emlyn Williams and Albert Hague, 1973 (Box 82 (Oversize))
    - Journal des Demoiselles, color plate mounted on board and calendar portfolio, 1865, 1960 (Box 83 (Oversize))
    - Collier's magazine issue, 1956 March 16 (Box 83 (Oversize))
    - The Theatre Illustrated Magazine of Dramatic and Musical Art, Vol. VI. no. 65, 1906 July (Box 83 (Oversize))
    - The Daily News issue (2 copies), 1987 June 15 (Box 83 (Oversize))
    - The New York Times issue (2 copies), 1987 June 15 (Box 83 (Oversize))
    - The New York Post issue (2 copies), 1987 June 15 (Box 83 (Oversize))
    - Clippings, undated; 3 (Box 83 (Oversize))
    - Memorabilia, undated (Box 84 (Oversize))
      Includes fan, cloth doll, padded satin hanger, toy and game pieces, costume jewelry, sewing materials, and keys with hotel tags.
    - Scrapbook containing photograph and clippings relating to Page, 1958-1969 (Box 85 (Oversize))
  - Christmas Memories, framed drawing, 1966 (Box 86)
  - "Wuthering Heights (1939), The Divorce of Lady X (1938), Beat the Devil (1953)", undated; YCALMSS774_0001; 1; 03:18:40 (Box 87, Item barcode 39002102369981)
  - Untitled, undated; 1; 00:26:06; Static can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 88, Item barcode 39002104611984)
    Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    Various content heard on the tape including the voices of Geraldine Page and Rip Torn's young children in the year 1968.
  - "Gerry, Go-Go, [Brosly?], Rip", undated; 1; 01:06:01; High background noise can be heard on the tape. A high amount of hum and static can be heard. The program is distorted at times. (Box 88, Item barcode 39002104611992)
  - Home movie, "Torn" (super 8 film), 1976; 1 (Box 88, Item barcode 39002104612008)
  - Film, undated; (1 16mm film) (Box 89 (Cold Storage))
  - Record Albums
    - Steve Elliot, X-Mas 1972, Madala publishing, inscribed by Elliot to Page., (1 7" record album) (Box 90 (Record Album Storage))
    - Summer and Smoke, La Gondrina, Presenting Miss Geraldine Page, 1 side, Paramount Pictures Music Department, undated; (1 12" record album) (Box 90 (Record Album Storage))
    - Laurette Taylor, Peg O' My Heart, Decca recording., 1950; (1 12" record album) (Box 90 (Record Album Storage))
    - "Last Final Session of the Actor's Studio, June 1961 with comments by Lee Strasberg", 1961 June; (2 12" record albums) (Box 90 (Record Album Storage))
  - Pencil drawings, undated (Box 91 (Broadside))